Kaluzy Tes



kaluzy@ymail.com



2026432894



linkedin.com/in/kaleab-tesfaye-4657378a

Summary

Self-motivated IT & Technical Specialist with experience configuring computers, servers and peripheral devices to work within established company. Highly effective at problem solving, communication, growth mindset delivering high levels of customer satisfaction and decision making with 8+ years of progressive IT experience.

I am a student on a web developer programming and I have gathered vast knowledge about using HTML5, CSS markup languages and JavaScript and other things that are related to this sector. I am always updated with new string of coding and browser compatibility. I love learning and implementing according to time.

Experience



Senior Information Technology Specialist

Triplotechs Solutions

Jan 2020 - Apr 2020 (4 months)

- Configured Restaurant POS printers to operate with terminals via serial/network interfaces and train staff to utilize all functions of software
- Installed equipment for data communications networks including cabling, switches, wireless routers, CCTV appliance and telephone systems
- Research and identify computer problems and maintain computer equipment and software to ensure secure and efficient operations
- Configure firewall solutions and implement checkpoint firewall rules according to business requirements



Restaurant Manager

Letena Ethiopian Restaurant

Jun 2018 - Mar 2020 (1 year 10 months)

- Maintain inventory and supplies of all necessary cocktail snacks, bar supplies, sodas, mixers, mealservice items and table settings. Manage costs to stay within TBC budget
- I came up with a way to increase sales by up-selling alcoholic wine, spirits and beverages to every guest streamlined our productivity and improved it by 20%
- Upgrade existing system to a new restaurant management and point of sale and management system that helps restaurants improve operations, increase sales and create a better guest experience
- Troubleshoot POS system, perform preventive maintenance, accomplish operations and organizations mission by completing related tasks
- Stayed up to date on menu changes to offer current and accurate information, answer questions and help customers select optimal meal choices based on individual preferences
- Performed complete opening, closing and shift change duties to keep restaurant working efficiently and teams ready to meet customer needs
- Provided highest level of prompt and friendly customer service which increased client base by 40 % promote long-term loyalty
- Trained incoming staff on restaurant's practices, culture and procedures to maximize job satisfaction and productivity

· Scheduled reservations and managed seating arrangements

Senior IT & Technical Support

MultiChoice Group

Feb 2012 - Jul 2018 (6 years 6 months)

- · Provide business-clients with efficient support regarding computer Software or Hardware operation to resolve problems through phone calls, emails, ticket resolutions system and site visit
- · Install Software, Operating system and applications, install peripherals and drivers, setting up LAN and configure resources and file sharing on different OS platforms
- Install and configure wireless network devices, Routers, Modems, Hubs, Switches, WLAN controllers
- Design or implement security systems, video surveillance, motion detectors and closed-circuit television systems to ensure proper installation and operation
- · Installed time and attendance, security door metal detectors scanner systems and components according to service orders and manufacturer instructions
- Design and maintain company's dynamic website resulting in 80 % increase in sales using Content Management System

Education



Generation USA

Certification, Junior Web Developer

Jul 2021 - Oct 2021

Write well designed efficient code by using best software development practices. Create website layout/ user interface by using standard HTML/CSS/JavaScript practices and integrate data from various backend services and databases.

Licenses & Certifications



Google Analytics Certification - Google

Issued Feb 2020 - Expires Feb 2021 45690520

Skills

Microsoft Office • Management • Troubleshooting • Microsoft SQL Server • Teamwork • Technical Support • Web Development • HTML • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • JavaScript